aa.com 2015-06-27

# American Airlines Privacy Policy On aa.com

Last updated February 20, 2015

  * Protecting your privacy

This Privacy Policy explains how American Airlines, Inc. and certain affiliates ("we," "us," "our," "American") collect, use, share, and protect information in connection with American services that refer or link to this Privacy Policy ("our Services"). The affiliates to which this Privacy Policy applies includes without limitation, Envoy Air Inc. We refer to American and its affiliates collectively as the "American Family." This Privacy Policy applies regardless of the type of device you use to access our Services.

By using our Services, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy is not a contract.

American reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the updated Policy here along with the date on which the Policy was changed. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy that affect the way we collect, use and/or share your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by including a "NEWLY UPDATED" label with the "PRIVACY POLICY" link on our Services for 30 days after any material changes are made.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "personally identifiable information" means information that identifies a particular individual, such as name, date of birth, address and telephone number.

  * Information we collect and how we collect it

In order to facilitate your travel and manage our business, we collect and maintain personally identifiable information about you. American collects personally identifiable information from many sources to understand and meet your needs. For example, we collect personally identifiable information about you from:

The personally identifiable information we collect about you through these various sources may include, but is not limited to:

  * Automatically collected information (including cookies and geolocation)

In addition to obtaining your personally identifiable information, when you use our Services, we may receive technical information such as your browser type, the type of operating system you use, your geolocation, the name of your internet service provider, and pages visited on our Services. American gets this information by using technologies, including cookies, web beacons, and mobile device geolocation to provide and improve our Services and advertising. We also use this information to verify that visitors meet the criteria required to process their requests and for reporting activity on our Services. For example, we may want to know how long the average user spends on our Services or which pages or features get the most attention. This automatically collected information may be combined with information that is personally identifiable in order to personalize our Services and advertising to your interests.

Additionally, American may combine the information we receive from you with information collected from other sources. This information may be used to provide offers and/or services specifically tailored to your interests in accordance with applicable laws.

### Cookies on our services

When you use our Services, you may receive cookies from us and the third parties that collect information on our Services. We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best possible experience on our Services. We also use cookies to show you advertising that is relevant to you. If you continue to browse our website without changing your web browser's or device's settings that control cookies, you agree to receive cookies when you use our Services.

However, if you prefer, you can change your cookie settings at any time. Most browsers have options that allow the visitor to control whether the browser will accept cookies, reject cookies, or notify the visitor each time a cookie is sent. You may elect to reject cookies by adjusting your settings, but doing so will limit the range of features available to you on our Services and most major websites that use cookies.

Our Services also occasionally use "local shared objects" (also known as "Flash cookies"). Like browser cookies, Flash cookies may be used for coordinating content delivery, website functionality, maintaining preferences, advertising, or analytics. Unlike browser cookies, "Flash cookies" are not stored in the browser, but can nevertheless be managed.

### What are the different types of cookies that American Airlines uses?

###### There are four types of cookies used on our Services:

  * Information collected by third parties on our Services

Some of the content, advertising, and functionality on our Services may be provided by third parties that are not affiliated with us. As noted above, these and other third parties may collect or receive technical information about your use of our Services, including through the use of cookies, web beacons, and other technologies, and this information may be collected over time and combined with information collected on different websites and online services.

For example, some of our Services include social network or other third-party plug-ins (such as Facebook’s "Like" button) that enable you to login to certain of our Services, to comment on content available on our Services, and to share things you find on our Services with your social network. The providers of these plug-ins may be able to collect information about you even if you do not click on or otherwise interact with the plug-in or widget and regardless of whether you have an account or other relationship with these social networks and third parties. If you use social network tools or visit social networking sites, you should read their privacy disclosures to learn what information they collect, use, and share.

Also, some third parties collect information about users of our Services in order to provide interest-based advertising (on our Services and elsewhere). These third parties may use the information they collect on our Services to make predictions about your interests in order to provide you ads (from us and other companies) across the internet. Some of these third parties may participate in an industry organization that gives users the opportunity to opt out of receiving ads that are tailored based on online activities. For more information about interest-based advertising and how to opt out, please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance.

  * Minors

Due to the nature of our Services, we may collect travel purchase information, which may include personally identifiable information, from children under the age of 13 when it is necessary to comply with the law, including federal aviation or security regulations, or as otherwise necessary to provide transportation needs and services. We may retain personally identifiable information when necessary to provide transportation and related services to a child under the age of 13. American does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 other than when necessary to comply with the law or for safety and security reasons.

If you are a parent or guardian of someone under the age of 13 who has provided personally identifiable information without your knowledge and consent, you may request we remove this information by emailing privacy@aa.com.

  * Security

When you buy an American Airlines ticket or access your AAdvantage account over the web, your web browser connects to our Services through SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). SSL is an industry-standard way to send information over the internet in a more secure way. SSL also ensures you are actually sending data to American and not someone who claims to be American.

Please note, however, that while American attempts to safeguard your personally identifiable information, no method of transmitting or storing electronic information is ever completely secure, and thus we make no warranty, express, implied, or otherwise, that your information will never be accessed, used or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. IN NO EVENT SHALL WE BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES (WHETHER CONSEQUENTIAL, DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, SPECIAL OR OTHERWISE) ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH, A THIRD PARTY'S UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION, REGARDLESS OF WHETHER SUCH DAMAGES ARE BASED ON CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, TORT OR OTHER THEORIES OF LIABILITY, AND ALSO REGARDLESS OF WHETHER WE ARE GIVEN ACTUAL OR CONSTRUCTIVE NOTICE THAT DAMAGES WERE POSSIBLE, EXCEPT AS PROVIDED UNDER APPLICABLE LAWS.

  * How your information will be used

### Our Services

We use personally identifiable information to complete transactions and fulfill requests for our products and services. For example, we require you to provide personally identifiable information when making a reservation to purchase airline tickets or related products and services such as renting cars or booking hotel rooms through an American Airlines Reservations Agent, travel agent, the aa.com website or other travel-related website, or enrolling in the AAdvantage and Business Extra programs.

### Administrative, marketing, analytical purposes

In addition to processing, confirming and fulfilling the travel or other services or products you request, American may use personally identifiable information for administrative, analytical, and marketing purposes such as information systems management, accounting, billing and audits, credit card processing and verification, customer-relations correspondence, and/or operation of the AAdvantage and Business Extra programs. American also uses personally identifiable information to identify, develop and market products and services that we believe you will value in accordance with applicable laws.

### Legal requirements

Please note that the laws and regulations of several countries require us to provide foreign and domestic government agencies with access to the personally identifiable information you disclose to us and data that we have about you and your travel plans, history, or status, including both before and after a flight arrives. American does not have control or knowledge of the storage and use of that data after it has been delivered to the respective government entity. Further, to the extent required by law, we may disclose personally identifiable information to government authorities, or to third parties pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process, and we may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to protect the rights or property of American, our customers, our Services, or its users.

  * With whom your information will be shared

American does not sell or share your personally identifiable information with third parties except in compliance with this Privacy Policy. We may disclose information to companies affiliated with American and/or unaffiliated third parties (i) to provide the products and services you have requested; and (ii) and for administrative, analytical, and marketing purposes but in each case only to the extent that these entities need the information to perform their services or as required by law. For example, we may provide information we collect about you to third parties to distribute promotions, sweepstakes, marketing surveys, focus groups, interviews and other opportunities offered by American. These third parties are restricted in the ways they can use the information they receive when providing services to American.

We may also disclose personally identifiable information to third parties, such as employers, who have arranged for discounts, purchased travel or other services on your behalf.

In addition, from time to time, we may share information with affiliated American companies such as Envoy Air Inc. and American Airlines Vacations, and with carefully-selected third party companies with which we have a business relationship, including AAdvantage and Business Extra participants. These companies may send you offers based on the information you have provided us. Where we are required by applicable law, we will seek your consent prior to sharing your personally identifiable information with such third parties for marketing purposes. Also, as described below, you can opt out of having your information shared with third parties for those parties' direct marketing purposes by emailing us at privacy@aa.com.

In the event we undergo a business transition involving another company, such as a merger, corporate reorganization, acquisition, the sale of all or a portion of our assets, or in the event of bankruptcy, information that we have collected from or about you or your devices may be disclosed to such other entity as part of the due diligence or business integration process and will be transferred to such entity as one of the transferred assets.

To the extent required by law, including without limitation, the requirements imposed under the Transportation Security Administration Secure Flight program, we may disclose personally identifiable information to government authorities, or to third parties pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process, and we may also use or disclose your information as permitted by law to protect the rights or property of American, our customers, our website, or its users.

### EU residents

The EU Data Protection Directive gives EU residents certain rights in relation to the personally identifiable information which we hold about you including a right to request a copy of the information and the right to request the correction of inaccurate or incorrect data. If you would like a copy of the personally identifiable information that we hold about you or would like to request the correction of such information, please email privacy@aa.com.

When you provide us with your information, you acknowledge that this information may be stored and processed on servers located anywhere in the World, including either inside or outside of the USA or the European Economic Area.

  * Opt out of marketing communications and sharing your information with third parties for direct marketing purposes

American's websites do not honor web browsers' Do-Not-Track signals. You do have choices, however, when it comes to your privacy and internet browsing.

As noted above, some third parties collect information about users of our Services in order to provide interest-based advertising elsewhere. Some of these companies provide online users with the ability to opt out of receiving interest-based advertising. Please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance to learn more about interest-based advertising and how to opt out of receiving such advertising from participating companies.

If you’re an AAdvantage member and you want to opt out of receiving marketing email, log in to your AAdvantage profile and update your preferences or contact AAdvantage Customer Service. Please note, you’ll continue to receive AAdvantage program updates and email products for which you’ve subscribed. If you’re a Business Extra member and you want to opt out of marketing emails, log in to the Business Extra website and update your preferences.

    * Log in to your AAdvantage profile and manage your email preferences

    * Contact AAdvantage Customer Service

If you’re not AAdvantage program member and you want to opt out of marketing emails, you can join the AAdvantage program and register your preferences or send an email with the word “unsubscribe” in the subject line to privacy@aa.com from the address you wish to unsubscribe. In addition, all marketing email from American will have valid opt-out links in the email. Please be aware that unsubscribing by email will unsubscribe all users at this address, even if they are registered AAdvantage members and Business Extra members with registered preferences.

If you want to opt out of receiving forms of communication from American other than marketing email, or if you want American to stop sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties for those parties' direct marketing purposes, please email privacy@aa.com with your request. Regardless of your opt-out preferences, we reserve the right to send you certain communications and share your information with third parties for administrative and analytical purposes.

Other companies or programs in the American Family may require different steps to change your preferences for participation. Please consult the privacy policies of the relevant companies or programs for further information.

  * Links to other sites

We'd also like to remind visitors that we provide additional links to resources we think you'll find useful. These links will lead you to sites that are not affiliated with American and may operate under different privacy practices. Our visitors are responsible for reviewing the privacy policies for such other websites, as we have no control over information that is submitted to these companies.

## Contact us

If you have other questions, comments or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact our Chief Privacy Officer, Steven Leist at privacy@aa.com.
